

Eric Cross

www.ericxcross.com eric.cross@sympatico.ca

+44 7935 673288

Designer and developer based in Edinburgh, UK / recent graduate of a 16 week software development course at CodeClan / Previous life as an industrial designer / Successful freelancer / Passionate athlete Looking for new opportunities in UX and digital product design.

Selected Projects



TREETRIP / CARBON IMPACT CALCULATOR

Miriam Boran and Alasdair Carstairs at CodeClan / 1 week in May 2019 Group project to develop a CO2e calculator that helps people understand the environmental impacts of their travel. Website developed using Vanilla Javascript / Webpack / HTML / CSS. www.ericxcross.com/treetrip



GETWORK / JOB SEEKING TOOL

Individual project at CodeClan / 1 week in April 2019
Usability focused desktop app to help fellow Codeclan students manage their job search. Developed in a one week sprint using Vanilla Ruby / PostgreSQL / Sinatra / HTML / CSS.
www.ericxcross.com/getwork



PROFIM / ELLIE CHAIR FAMILY DESIGN STRATEGY

Industrial Designer at ITO Design / June 2017 - Oct 2018
Ergonomic chair family that responds to the merging traditions of home and office. Led market research, design research, and creative direction, facilitated client workshops, involved in design and CMF development. www.ito-design.com/projects/2018_profim_ellie_de/



MCDONALD'S AUSTRALIA / SELF SERVE EXPERIENCE

Freelancer for Blue Sky Design Group / April - June 2016
A new customer journey to transition restaurants to digital (self serve) ordering. Roles included research, wireframing of current experience and creating guidelines for new flow, zoning, and digital kiosk placement. www.blueskydesigngroup.com.au/project/mcdonalds/

Education

CODECLAN

SQA LEVEL 8 IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Edinburgh, UK Feb - June 2019 16 week course to gain an understanding of the software development process as it relates to UX design. Agile structure with 4 weeks classroom learning interspersed with 1 week project sprints.

CARLETON UNIVERSITY

BACHELORS OF INDUSTRIAL DESIGN

Ottawa, Canada Sept 2011 - June 2016 Four year degree with course requirements in psychology, business and design. Undergraduate thesis conducted with Herman Miller to solve issues around supply storage and administration in Canadian ICUs. Awarded a Provost Scholarship for academic research in 2016.

Professional Experience

SELF-EMPLOYED

FREELANCE DESIGNER

Feb 2015 - Ongoing

Currently Edinburgh, UK Experienced freelancer and subcontractor for projects in healthcare, furniture, spacial design, and tech. Services included market research, usability research, speculative design, experience design, concept development, and design for manufacture.

ITO DESIGN INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER

Cham, Switzerland June 2016 - Sept 2018

Design studio specializing in design for the office environment. Part of a small team researching and designing new products from conception to production. Directly involved in client interactions and project management. Focus on usability and functional innovations in the ergonomic furniture and seating markets.

OTI LUMIONICS

DESIGN INTERN

Toronto, Canada May - Aug 2015

Startup in the OLED manufacturing industry. Roles included designing OLED lighting concepts, creating retail and brand engagement pieces and content creation for the OTI and Aerelight website.

BLUE SKY EXPERIENCE DESIGN INTERN

Sydney, Australia June 2014 - Dec 2014

Consultancy focused on customer experience and spatial design. Heavily involved in a branch transformation project for ANZ bank in Australia. Conducted secondary research, site visits, supplier surveys, user flows, spatial diagrams and facilitated design workshops. Continued freelancing for Blue Sky on related projects until 2016.

Software / Skills

Design Adobe XD / Photoshop / Illustrator / Indesign

Software Dev | S / Java / Ruby / Processing

Web Dev HTML / CSS / Sinatra (ruby) / Webpack(JS) **Frameworks** React (JS) / Express(JS) / Spring (Java)

Databases PostgreSQL / MongoDB

Versioning Git / Github

3D Modelling Rhino 3D (NURBS) / Solidworks (NURBS / Grasshopper (algorithmic) /

T-Splines (Sub-D) / Keyshot (Rendering)

Languages English (Native) / French (Professional Working Proficiency) /

German (Elementary Proficiency)

Links

Portfolio www.ericxcross.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/ericxcross **GitHub** www.github.com/ericxcross

Email eric.cross@sympatico.ca

Phone +44 7935 673288